[intriguing music playing]
[detective 1] We're trying to collect
as much information as we can
to get a clear picture on what's going on
and figure out where to start. okay?
-[Jack] Okay.
-[detective 1] Um… Starting yesterday.
-did you go to the football game?
-[Jack] No. I was at work.
[detective 1] What did you do
after you got off shift?
[Jack] I went home
and met up with my friends.
and then we went to the Corner Club.
[Anthony] We identified Jack
as the ex-boyfriend of Kaylee.
He was very open and honest about
his knowledge of what was going on.
He explained their history
between he and Kaylee.
and how their relationship was.
and how long it lasted. and how it ended.
[Jack] Eventually. I came back home.
-[detective 1] Have roommates? They there?
-[Jack] Mm-hm. Yeah.
[officer 1] What time did you guys
make it home from the bar?
[man] 1:30ish.
-[officer 1] You were with him all night?
-[man] Mm-hmm.
[Anthony] And so. through following up
on some of the evidence that he shared
of his whereabouts
and his alibis for that evening.
we were able to eliminate him
as a potential suspect.
[detective 1] You're not in trouble.
I just gotta ask questions.
Talk me through the rest of your evening.
You guys hang out?
[Jack] I came back home.
Pretty much just went to bed.
[detective 1] You had missed calls from
Kaylee. Remember what time. by chance?
[Jack] Yeah. they were.
like. between 2:40 and 3:00.
The last one was. like. 2:57.
Kaylee has called me and stuff.
like. if she's walking home.
and she thinks someone. like.
is watching or following her.
she'll call me and just…
-Just to have someone on the phone.
-[detective 1] Yeah. yeah.
Did she ever mention that
she thought someone was following her.
or was it more just getting creeped out?
[Jack] Yeah. just got creeped out.
Um. ever had any roommates
complain about anyone stalking them?
[Bethany] Mm-mm.
Once though. Kaylee said
when everyone was. like. gone
and it was only Kaylee
and she was taking Murphy out.
and she said she swears
she saw someone staring at her
while she was taking the dog out to pee.
She could see. like.
a man's silhouette staring at her.
-Know how long ago that was?
-[Bethany] Maybe like a month.
[intriguing music continues]
[Dylan] About a week ago.
our door is broken
but me. Maddie and Bethany got home
and the door was wide open.
[detective 2] Did you ever. uh.
find the back slider open or anything?
-Is that usually locked?
-[Dylan] We're pretty good at locking it.
I don't think we locked it last night.
[Jack] There's a lot of people coming in
and out of their house all the time
just because they're well-liked people.
[detective 3] This may seem like
a weird question.
but who would do something like this?
[Dylan] I couldn't even imagine.
[tense music playing]
[music swelling]
[music becomes quiet]
[music fades]
[intriguing music playing]
[Ed] During the time
of the Moscow homicides.
I was a Special Agent in the
Coeur d'Alene resident agency of the FBI.
Moscow PD just needed a lot of resources
at a moment's notice.
I drove down to Moscow.
walked into Chief Fry's office
and offered assistance. and explained
what we could do from the FBI standpoint.
The chief told us. "Bring it."
and that's where we came in
to assist the investigation.
[detective 4] We're just trying
to put the pieces of the puzzle together.
um. just with everything that's going on.
[Anthony] Everybody who had
any information.
we needed to talk to them.
to interview them.
[Ed] In this particular case.
we did not have a clear intended victim.
You don't just have a single homicide.
you have four different kids.
[Anthony] Immediately.
we dug into the personal relationships
of each of the victims.
We're gonna go back and try
to get a little bit of the timeline. okay?
[Bethany] Yeah.
[Ed] We call it "victimology."
investigating the lives of the victims.
Tracking friends. tracking family.
tracking movement to determine
who they've come across
that has a problem with them.
has a motive to actually hurt them.
[Anthony] To do that.
we needed to create a timeline
of that evening
and into the early hours of that morning.
and try to find some sort of a connection.
[detective 2] When was the last time
that you were over at…?
[Hunter J.] The last time
before today was yesterday.
[detective 2] Okay.
What were you doing there yesterday?
[Hunter J.] We were pre-gaming
the football game for the Vandals.
[detective 2] Gotcha.
[Hunter J.] We left their house
and went to a different apartment
at roughly. like. 2:30.
[people shouting]
[Kristi] Saturday it was a football game.
There was a lot of people in town.
It was the last home game of the year.
Kaylee was really excited about it.
She texted me a picture of her and Maddie.
And I replied. "My lovies!"
And then she called me.
and I had bought her some succulents.
She had to tell me quick
this rambling little story
of how the succulents were doing.
She said. "Mom.
we're gonna come home take a nap
and gonna go out tonight."
[intriguing music continues]
And I said. "Okay. have fun!
I love you guys."
[Peter] That day.
I went and pre-gamed with Ethan.
We hung out on the couch and had a beer.
And Ethan was upset
that I was leaving the pre-game.
He was like.
"Screw it. Can I just come with you?"
Later in that night.
we went to Kappa Alpha Theta's formal.
Ethan's sister.
Maizie's in that sorority. also.
Ethan was a triplet.
He was inseparable from his siblings.
Maizie didn't have a date.
so Maizie took Ethan as her date.
We went to that formal. That was fun.
That was one of
the funnest nights of my life.
Xana didn't go to that.
She kinda did her own thing
until after the formal.
[Bethany] We were just hanging out
at our house.
Ethan was at formal
because he went with his sister
because she didn't have a date.
And then he came over
and then we all walked over together.
And the last time you saw
Xana and Ethan was at the Sigma Chi house?
-Mm.
-Okay.
You. Ethan. Xana…
Was there another person with you?
-Or just three of you that walked?
-Uh. Maddie walked over with us.
[Cooper] I remember hanging out
with Ethan and Xana that night.
I remember talking about his family.
and being grateful for that conversation.
And something that. I don't know why
God gave me this moment.
but I hugged them both
and I said. "I love you both." Um…
That's something I'll never forget.
Were you guys all together.
or just kind of mingling
throughout the house?
We were all pretty much together
and then Maddie left
to go to the club with Kaylee.
[Alivea] At this point.
we're still driving to my parents' house.
My kids are sleeping in the back here.
I have nothing but time.
I keep going through Kaylee's phone logs.
And I just start texting
some phone numbers
of people that she had communicated with.
"You talked to my sister at 1:07 a.m.?"
Someone would tell me.
"Yes. I did. I was told this.
but so-and-so might have more
information. here's their number."
So I would contact so-and-so.
I'm just trying to find anything I can.
I reach out to the driver who had given
Kaylee and Maddie a ride out that night
and then also take them
back home that night.
I learned from this individual
sometime shortly after 10:00 p.m.
They were picked up to go out.
and this driver dropped them off
at the Corner Club.
[detective 1] What happened next?
[Jack] I did run into Kaylee
at the Corner Club.
said hi to her. talked to her
for probably a minute or so.
I don't even really remember what our…
We had a 30-second conversation.
[detective 1] Okay.
Did it seem normal? Did it seem off?
-[Jack] Yeah. everything seemed normal.
-[detective 1] Okay.
[detective 5] So. what…
Let's go a little bit more.
[Bethany] They went to Grub Truck
after the club.
Okay.
[Maya] Outside the Corner Club.
there's this little. uh. food truck
called the Grub Truck.
Disgusting if you're sober.
If you're drunk. it's phenomenal.
-I understand.
-Pizza mac? You got it.
[Anthony] We had found out that Kaylee
and Maddie had been to the Grub Truck.
We at the police department had been aware
that they had a Twitch feed.
which is an online video feed
of their business. basically.
And people are able to go on there
and make comments.
and we'd utilized that information
through them previously for other cases.
You know. we've had things go on downtown
that maybe got captured on that camera.
so we knew
we definitely needed to look at that.
[intriguing music continues]
[Alivea] I didn't know to look
organically. Someone tipped me off
that this Grub Truck did this.
Maybe it caught Kaylee and Maddie on it.
I just start watching.
you know. just fast-forwarding bits.
-Hello!
-Hi.
Welcome back.
Thanks. I think I would like the. um…
[Alivea] Kaylee and Maddie
come into the screen.
I'm able to recognize them right away.
Everything to me is looking fairly normal.
[Anthony] We watched Kaylee and Maddie
appearing to be very happy
and just enjoying the rest
of their late evening.
They were ordering some food.
but we as investigators
aren't particularly focused on that.
We're looking at
what's going on around them
and what are the other people doing
around them.
and there were some things going on
that would raise suspicion.
We recognized this male in a hood.
hooded sweatshirt.
"Hoodie Guy." as he was coined.
Approached them. spoke to them briefly.
And then once the girls walked out
of view of the camera.
we could see that
this individual in a hoodie followed them.
So. we're gonna look at that and go.
"Okay. there might be something there."
We needed to find more video surveillance
of this individual
in a hoodie in the area.
[reporter] I've been here in Moscow
on scene since about 3:00 p.m.
Since I've been here.
I've watched Moscow police cars
come in and out of this neighborhood
where officials found four people dead.
[officer 1] Well. it's all over the news.
The rumor out there is
somebody died here from fentanyl.
And then somebody else said
somebody might have got stabbed.
I said.
"Well. I can't confirm any of that."
So… But the rumors are out there.
Oh. yeah.
Yeah. there were rumors being spread
all over the place
about maybe it was drugs
or some sort of connection with cartels.
-[officer 2] Are you guys out of here?
-Yeah.
-[officer 2] I'll mark you off.
-All right.
[Anthony] Of course. we didn't know
who the target was. what the motive was.
But it was pretty apparent to us that
for an individual to go into a residence
and kill four people with an edged weapon.
that was purposeful.
[moody dramatic music playing]
[Kristi] We didn't know
what to do. There's…
just shock.
Everyone was coming
to me and Kristi for answers.
We were looking very forward to
seeing somebody who was actually there.
-So. Jack shows up at our house.
-The next day.
[Steve] And we're basically
more like bees. We swarmed him.
He came into the house
and we said. "What's going on?"
Jack couldn't get a hold of us
because they took his phone.
The day before. at the police station.
obviously they were questioning him.
We went through. "What did they do?
Did they interview? What did they say?"
What do you know?
What was she doing? Where was she going?
Jack said. "All I know is this."
He said he was sitting in the hall
of the police department. I'm imagining.
And there are several people there
waiting to talk to the police.
And he overheard…
Dylan talking
to what he assumed was her parents.
Somewhere in the night. Dylan saw a man
all dressed in black with a mask.
And I said. "An intruder?"
"You're telling me there was…"
I remember using that word.
"There was an intruder.
Came into their house. was in the house."
And he's like.
"I don't know. Kristi. I don't know."
I'm like. "Jack. you gotta… you know."
and he's just frazzled.
He's. like. you know.
piecing things together.
He doesn't want
and say something that's not true.
He's like. "That's all I remember."
[dramatic music playing]
[reporter] It was a solemn day
here in Moscow.
A campus ordinarily packed with students
and energy. quiet and empty.
Many trying to process this tragedy.
It was an uneasy feeling
at the University of Idaho.
[Cooper] People are trying to piece
together who. what. where. why. how.
[Peter] All the guys in the house
were kinda restless.
walking around the courtyard talking.
like. "What the hell happened?"
[Cooper] Then I went home
that following day.
which most of everyone did.
No one wanted to be there.
[melancholic music playing]
[Tami] As family. we all gathered.
We all. you know.
talk about it. cry about it.
Try to eat. try to get Kristi to eat.
you know. try to take care of each other.
It was horrible here.
It was horrible. Kristi lost her daughter.
You know. my son lost his daughter.
The girls lost their sibling.
their sister.
♪ Happy birthday. dear Kaylee
Happy bir… ♪
Moscow PD is contacting my dad
via phone call. I think most of the time.
with whatever information.
There's not a whole lot.
We didn't find out their…
manner of death until…
I think. 48 hours after it had happened.
[Tami] Kristi called me.
and I said. "What's going on?"
And she goes.
"We found out what happened."
I was like. "What? Were they shot?"
She says. "No. they were stabbed."
And I was like.
"What? What do you mean?"
She said. "They were all stabbed to death.
we were told today."
And I was like…
[haltingly] I don't even think. like.
you don't know what to think
when someone tells you that.
[Kristi] The coroner called me
and confirmed to us
that Maddie and Kaylee
were in bed together.
and that a very large knife
with a seven-inch blade
was used.
Yeah.
[Jeff] I just couldn't understand that.
[melancholic music continues]
It's just such a wrong thing…
to. to have to deal with.
and it's everybody's worst nightmare.
The night of the 12th and the 13th.
I was at the WSU game with Jazzmin.
I was thinking. "You know what?"
"I should give Xana a call.
Maybe I'll stay at her house tonight."
And I kinda thought about it.
And I drank quite a bit that night.
And I go. "You know what?"
"Xana'd probably get mad
if I drove over there." so I didn't go.
But I could've gone.
and things would have been different.
Maybe they would've
had a chance. you know?
Some of them.
Yeah.
[ominous music playing]
[news anchor 1] Let's turn to new details
in the case that is gripping the nation.
the shocking murders
of four University of Idaho students.
Yeah. days after their tragic deaths.
police have yet to identify a suspect.
and it's left a small college town
on edge this morning.
[Ed] Majority of homicide cases.
a suspect appears quickly.
[knocking on door]
When you get into something like this
where it just isn't happening.
this is what in law enforcement
we refer to the "whodunnit."
where you don't have
a fairly immediate suspect in the case.
The word's getting out.
the pressures come.
and the answers aren't there yet.
And so. you start expanding out.
[news anchor 2] Law enforcement's
latest efforts have been sifting through
surveillance videos from downtown
and any doorbell cameras
in the area of the crime scene.
[news anchor 3]
Volunteers put up flyers on store windows
asking anyone who has
a home camera. a security camera.
to look for anything suspicious
the night of the murders.
We were able to gather
every bit of video footage
from that time frame
in the entire Moscow area.
[Anthony] We had detectives
sitting for hours on end
-re-watching footage over and over again.
-[dramatic music playing]
We were able to work with all of the folks
involved in the Grub Truck video.
There were lots of people around. We ended
up identifying all of those people.
We were able to identify Hoodie Guy.
-[Hathaway] This is Sergeant Hathaway.
-[Hoodie Guy] How's it going?
[Hathaway] How we doing?
-[Hoodie Guy] I want to make a statement.
-[Hathaway] Okay. what's going on?
[Hoodie Guy] I'm just friends with Maddie.
I was with her at the bar that night.
We left to get Grub Truck. and then
she got picked up in a silver Sedan.
That's my only description I know.
And then they went home from there.
All of the information that he gave
showed us that he was not involved.
and we did the same thing with
the ride-share driver that picked them up.
[Hathaway] Okay. Well--
[Hoodie Guy]
Yeah. she just got in a silver Sedan.
[Hathaway] But you don't know
who it was or anything?
[Hoodie Guy]
I didn't see who the driver was.
[Anthony] The driver
that we identified later in an interview
said when Kaylee and Maddie
got in the car. they were happy.
They didn't seem to be upset
or suspicious
of the individual or anything else.
They were just having a good time.
heading home with their food
from the Grub Truck.
as many college students do
on a Saturday night.
Police continue to pour through evidence
and conduct interviews.
all to try and find out how these four
University of Idaho students were killed.
[Brian] They're working on establishing
where everybody was that night.
They've gotten about 500 tips so far.
They have 22 FBI investigators that
they've brought in to help with this case.
But for this community.
this case remains in the same place.
No murder weapon.
no suspect. and no motive.
Early on. people were texting me
about the story
and said. "Have you heard
about this story in Idaho?"
"There's these four college kids
that were murdered."
"No one knows who did it."
"It's really. really intense.
and I think you should get out there."
I remember looking into it and deciding.
"I'm gonna go to Idaho and see what's up."
Around that same time
that the national media started arriving.
so did the online sleuths. the YouTubers.
and that's when the rumor mill started.
Misinformation. speculation.
theories fueled the flame
of everyone's imagination.
and we were inundated.
[Brian] At the time.
the police were not talking very much.
and so internet sleuths. people at home.
started trying to investigate
on their own.
[intriguing music playing]
[sleuth 1] So Dylan does have a boyfriend.
Just wanted to bring that up.
I'm not saying he has anything
to do with it. Could he possibly?
I have a theory about this Idaho 4 case
and I want people to listen to this.
[Brian] There were just wild theories
at this point.
And suddenly. you know.
every day there was a new theory
about what might have happened.
[sleuth 2] You know and I know
that crime was filmed.
It is on the dark web.
The physical description
of the Moscow killer was revealed to me
in downloaded information
from the universal consciousness.
They started trying to investigate
people from the fraternity.
which is right across the street
from the house.
[sleuth 3]
This is the Sigma Chi fraternity.
This is where one of the victims.
Ethan Chapin. went to.
Door is open.
[Cooper] There were accusations
flying left and right.
There were just no answers.
and so people were…
finding answers themselves.
[sleuth 3] If somebody from one of these
university fraternities are involved.
university students.
and other students know.
and they're just. they're scared.
[Cooper] I got Facebook messages.
Twitter messages. Instagram DMs.
all asking. what do I know?
Why aren't I saying anything?
I got a few of those messages.
People saying that I'm the killer.
saying that I'm gonna get arrested.
I'm gonna get caught. I can't
keep running. Like. what are you saying?
[Cooper] It's hard
because all of us were processing it.
trying to deal with our friends
that just got killed.
and also protect ourselves
from the internet.
[Peter] I don't understand how people
get pleasure saying that.
I feel horrible. I can't imagine
what Dylan and Bethany get.
It's horrible.
[sleuth 4] Dylan Mortensen
is guilty. you guys.
You know what she is guilty of?
Not calling 911 for her friends.
"How is it possible
that they wouldn't call 911 sooner?"
"They must know something."
There was other people in the house
when these four people are murdered.
I 100% believe that this girl
heard and saw so much more
than we are getting right now.
[contemplative music playing]
Shock and trauma
do a lot of damage to people.
It can impair judgment.
It can impair thought processes.
I don't blame them
for making the call a little late.
I can only imagine
what was going through their minds.
If it were me
in either one of their shoes.
I would have never believed
what occurred in that house that night.
On the phone with the coroner. we asked
if somebody would've called 911.
-At a particular moment that night…
-Yes.
…could Ethan have lived?
Could Xana have lived?
Could somebody have been saved?
And the answer was no.
[Steve] It's hard for us. because you go
back and look at all these moments
and you wish
you could do things different.
And Jack felt the same way.
[Cheryl] Jack was just lost.
you know what I mean?
It was so hard. it was so hard on Jack
because of all the rumors.
[Baylie] The rumors
that went around and around
were that Jack. my cousin. had done this.
And seeing him in this dark place
was really hard and sad.
And then to see people online
tear him apart
after. you know. he's already
going through what he's going through…
Um…
It was. it was really heartbreaking.
[Kaylee] Jack. say hi!
Sup?
[Baylie] Social media got to be
kind of a more scary place
than like… than a place
to really look for any answers.
[melancholic music playing]
[James] Good afternoon.
We are thankful for all the tips
and leads the public has provided
in Ethan. Xana. Kaylee.
and Madison's murder investigation.
No bit of information is too small.
and every tip will be pursued.
We do not believe
the following individuals were involved.
The two surviving roommates.
the male seen in a Grub Truck video
circulating on the internet.
a private party
who drove Kaylee and Madison home.
any of the individuals who spoke
to the dispatcher on the 911 call.
We're also aware of a male whom
Madison and Kaylee had called
several times
the morning of November 13th.
and we do not suspect that individual.
We will continue to work hard
and continue to do everything we can.
We want people to be vigilant. want people
to report anything suspicious to us
and let us handle it.
I wanna thank you today for coming.
and I appreciate your questions.
[intriguing music playing]
[Alivea] We were sitting
waiting for an arrest.
Waiting for a suspect. an assailant.
Uh. there was no information.
We had a thousand questions.
We have no real indication of what way
this is going. Is this going cold?
From the beginning. Steve took
the reins and said. "We're fighting."
"We are not letting this die down."
"We're going to make sure
there is attention on this case."
"We are going to make sure
that we scream to the rooftop."
I don't know how you catch a criminal
if you don't know what you're looking for.
[news anchor] Steven Goncalves
sharing his fear and frustration.
not only facing the heartbreaking loss
of his daughter Kaylee
and her three friends.
but the fact that their killer
is still at large.
It's gonna be a cold case if we don't
do something within the next week or two.
The amount of damage something like this
does to a family is inexcusable.
As a dad. you wanna come that much harder
on the person who's responsible.
You didn't do it once.
you didn't do it twice.
you didn't do it three.
you did four times.
And if you play God.
then we're gonna hold you accountable.
[dramatic music playing]
[news anchor 1]
For two weeks and two days.
the brutal slaying
of Ethan Chapin. Madison Mogen.
Xana Kernodle. and Kaylee Goncalves
has gone unsolved.
[news anchor 2] Police in Moscow assure
everyone progress is being made.
but with the killer still at large.
this fear absolutely remains.
[Anthony] We had so much noise
coming at us from the world at large.
Everyone's eyes are on you.
and it can feel pretty lonely and pretty…
When you're under that microscope.
it's tough. but we had to keep going.
Finally. we were contacted
by the Idaho State Police lab in Meridian.
who told us that they had found
a single-source male DNA
from the snap on that knife sheath.
[intriguing music playing]
They had developed a profile
based on that.
They put it through the CODIS system.
which is our national DNA database.
but had received no hits.
The DNA on the knife sheath did not match
any one particular person.
So whose DNA is this?
The next step was
to hand-deliver that profile
to the Othram labs in Texas to begin
the investigative genetic genealogy.
[Ed] Investigative genetic genealogy
takes the DNA sampling
through commercially-available databases
where people have submitted their DNA
to find their family histories.
From that. you find distant relatives.
and you start building family trees
to try to come up with a group of suspects
from an unknown DNA sample.
It was very exciting that we had
a new development in the case.
but we couldn't hang our hat on that.
So as soon as the lab received that item.
they went to work.
but we kept working on our end.
In the initial canvassing of the area
was actually when we recognized that there
was a camera on the neighboring home.
-[detective 1] You have a camera.
-[woman 1] Yes.
-[detective 1] Have other cameras?
-[woman 1] Just that one.
-[detective 1] How big? Mind if I see?
-[woman 1] The road. it cuts out…
[woman 2] Just the driveway.
Our detectives recognized that immediately
and seized that camera
and all of its components.
brought that back to the department
and started working.
-[woman 1] Here's the SD card.
-[detective 2] I appreciate that.
-[woman 1] Of course.
-[detective 3] Thank you.
Video is considered vanishing evidence.
Different cameras have different
write-over times.
different save times.
and you don't know what that is.
So. it's very critical you get all video
footage you can
as fast as possible.
[Anthony] Our detectives
who had seized the neighbor's camera
had been able
to more or less get into the system.
And initially. they were only able
to retrieve video. there was no audio.
But they were eventually able to combine
the two and get the video and audio.
It was very clear
that we had something here.
[dramatic music playing]
Starting in the early hours of the 13th.
this white car is seen
in the area of 1122 King Road.
We see it come and go from the area.
sometimes a little bit slowly.
several times.
[Ed] Between approximately 3:30 a.m.
and 4:06 a.m..
the vehicle is seen entering
and leaving the area four times.
[Anthony] And then
the final time. at 4:20 a.m.
[dog barking]
[tires screech]
This white car is seen again on the camera
leaving at a high rate of speed.
almost seemingly crashing
on the way out of the neighborhood.
Prior to the car leaving the area.
Xana's phone records show
that she had ordered a DoorDash.
and that DoorDash was delivered
at approximately 4:00 a.m.
She was awake. scrolling on social media.
up until about 4:12 in the morning.
So we know that between 4:12.
when Xana is awake and active.
and 4:20. when that vehicle is speeding
out of the area for the last time.
during that time frame.
these murders occurred.
This is our person. This is our suspect.
You can't see much detail
in a car on a camera at night
because headlights. taillights wash out
most of the detail of the car.
[Anthony] Our investigators sent out
that video to the FBI.
where they have vehicle experts.
We also found surveillance footage
from other areas around Moscow.
[Ed] They look at details of it.
window shape. size. comparisons.
And they could only narrow it down
to three or four different makes
and models that it could have been.
As we were getting more vehicle feed.
we would send clips to them
to determine if we could develop
a make. model. and year.
We got some distance video
from an apartment complex.
Another residential camera
a couple miles away.
We got taillights.
So. they started adding that
to the collection
to try to narrow down the vehicle.
And we finally got a clear shot
of a side profile of the vehicle
under a streetlight.
It wasn't washed out by its own lights.
The vehicle identification analyst
was able at that point to say.
this is a Hyundai Elantra
between the years of 2011 to 2016.
And then on December 19th.
we received a call from the FBI's
investigative genealogical team.
and the team leader said.
"We have a name."
"Bryan Kohberger."
[intriguing music playing]
He attends Washington State University
and he drives a white Hyundai Elantra.
[man] Lincoln. Frank. Zebra. 8-6-4-9.
[Ed] We opened up the investigation
into Bryan Kohberger.
[Anthony] And we started getting
information immediately.
-[deputy] Hey there.
-Hi.
I stopped you going a little fast.
Do you realize this is. uh. 35?
-Oh. it's 35?
-It is. yeah. So you were going--
-About 41?
-Yeah. 43 was what the radar said.
Immediately. we found a deputy
had pulled Kohberger over one evening
in a white Hyundai Elantra for.
I believe. a speeding violation.
and ended up issuing him a citation
for not wearing a seat belt.
Because of that citation. we had the cell
phone number belonging to Kohberger.
which was utilized
in obtaining search warrants
and getting cell phone data.
-[deputy] Can I get a phone number?
-Yeah. why?
Uh. we need to put it on the citation
as it goes to the court.
[Anthony] One of the first things we saw
was his phone had pinged off of towers
that service the area of Moscow
many times over the course
of several months
prior to the November 13th incident.
His typical pathway
from his residence in Pullman was.
as most people here would use.
is the Moscow-Pullman highway.
It's the direct link
between Pullman and Moscow.
And we could see that he'd made
several trips into Moscow to shop.
We had cell phone data
of him in local stores.
It's not out of the ordinary
for college students to do that.
especially with WSU and University
of Idaho being so close together.
[ominous music playing]
But when we started narrowing in
on King Road.
we saw his phone
in that area multiple times.
Very odd hours. late at night.
That really started
linking things together.
On the night of the murders.
November 12th into the 13th.
at approximately 2:42 a.m..
Kohberger's phone was connecting
to cell phone towers
that serviced his residence in Pullman.
[car engine starts]
At approximately 2:47.
he left his residence.
began moving south through Pullman.
Kohberger's phone then went dark.
It was shortly after that
the white Elantra enters
the area of the crime scene.
During that time frame is when we know
that these murders occurred.
At approximately 4:48.
Kohberger's phone reactivates
onto cellular data.
and it is seen being south of Moscow
on Highway 95.
[contemplative music playing]
And then at approximately 5:30 a.m..
Kohberger's phone is seen connecting
to a cell phone tower again
near his residence.
[Ed] The loop where he's left the house
from that area and going into farmland
and coming up on the south side of Pullman
took about an hour and ten minutes
for him to get back.
It was a bit odd.
but when you think about it.
a KA-BAR knife. even though
it's a rather large knife or as knives go.
it's a small object.
And there's an insurmountable
amount of places
where something like that could end up.
What we really found interesting was
immediately after November 13th.
Bryan Kohberger never came back
to Moscow as he did prior.
We also found through search warrants
for his credit cards and his financials
that he had stopped coming to Moscow
buying anything. period.
So this very starkly different behavior
after November 13th started to develop.
[contemplative music continues]
[Ed] At this point. Bryan Kohberger
becomes our suspect in the case.
but investigative genealogy
is not court-admissible evidence.
We knew that we needed to be able to link
the DNA on that knife sheath to Kohberger.
[police siren blares]
[Ed] Once we started running checks.
we learned that on December 15th.
Bryan had been pulled over
in the Elantra twice in Indiana
for following vehicles too close.
-[officer 1] Hello. How y'all doing today?
-How you doing?
[officer 1] Good. good.
So you was right up on that van. man.
[Ed] His father
was in the vehicle with him.
[officer 1] You're coming
from Washington State University?
-Yeah.
-[officer 1] And you're going where?
-We're gonna be going to Pennsylvania.
-[officer 1] Okay.
[Ed] We determined
that he was traveling back
to his parents' house in Pennsylvania.
[Anthony] The house was relatively normal
on a quiet. little street.
We worked with our FBI partners back east.
and they immediately started surveilling
the residence and Kohberger himself.
[suspenseful music playing]
They did witness some.
for lack of a better term.
strange behavior.
He was seen both in the home
and outside the home in public
wearing rubber gloves.
[Ed] Any time he would leave the house.
the FBI were attempting
to find what we call "discarded DNA."
Something that somebody leaves behind
that would contain their DNA
that can be collected
by the surveillance agents.
But during the course of a week.
he only left the house three times.
So it was decided to do what
in law enforcement we call a "trash pull."
When trash is put out to the curb.
it's considered abandoned at that point.
and we can legally seize that trash
and… and collect it.
On Tuesday the 27th.
we knew it was trash day.
The agent arrived at 4:00 a.m.
to confirm the trash was there
before grabbing it.
and Bryan was actually walking
down the street at that time.
The agent called me up and said. "I just
saw Bryan walking down the street."
We collected the trash.
Any items that could have contained DNA
were collected from that trash
and all that evidence arrived
at the Idaho State Police lab at 1:00 a.m.
They had all of their technicians in
and started processing that evidence.
We found a Q-tip
within that trash that was tested.
and it tested that the DNA on that Q-tip
belonged to the father of the person
whose DNA was on that knife sheath.
There was only one male son
in that family.
It was Bryan Kohberger.
We had him.
[woman] I got the notification on my phone
that the Idaho perpetrator was arrested.
I pull up a picture.
and I almost passed out.
I felt the blood leave my face.
I was horrified.
It was the person
sitting next to me in class.
[ominous music playing]
[music fades]
[moody electronic music playing]